Guide to the Joanna Po nursing career awards and academic records, 1985-2014 MS 762
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Joanna Po nursing career awards and academic records
1985-2014
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Po, Joanna
MS 762
3 Linear Feet 1 box
The collection includes academic and nursing certification records, as well as nursing career awards for Joana Po's distinguished service, from the 1980s through the 2000s.
Biographical / Historical
Joanna Villarena Po was born on September 11, 1943 in Balasan, Iloilo, Philippines, one of ten children. Of her five brothers and four sisters she was the only one who came to America on her own, but she eventually sponsored two of her brothers to come later in life. When she was younger, her brother helped her complete her bachelor's degree in nursing in the Philippines. Afterwards she came to work at Houston Methodist Hospital. She received her master's degree at Texas Woman's University. She met her husband through a Filipino social group in Houston and they have two daughters. Later on in life she owned a jewelry business which she eventually gave up to be able to spend more time traveling and with her grandchildren.
In 2014, Po was interviewed by the Houston Asian American Archive oral histories program, and the interview is online at https://scholarship.rice.edu/handle/1911/77533. Throughout the interview, Po discusses incidences of discrimination she has endured as an Asian woman living in the United States, as well as general differences between her life in the Philippines and her life in the U.S.
Scope and Contents
Academic and nursing certification records, as well as nursing career awards for Joana Po's distinguished service, from the 1980s through the 2000s.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is stored onsite at the Woodson Research Center.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Joanna Po, 2018.
Related Materials
Joanna Po was interviewed for the Houston Asian American Archive oral history project in 2014, and that interview is online at https://scholarship.rice.edu/handle/1911/77533.
Index Terms
Subjects
Health care and medicine; Asian Americans
Subjects (Persons)
Po, Joanna
- Series I: Academic records
  - Texas Woman's University Master of Science diploma, August 17, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Board of Nurse Examiners for the State of Texas, Advanced Practice Nurse, April 1, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Nurses Credentialing Center Board Certification as a Medical-Surgical Nurse from Dec. 1, 1994 to Nov. 30, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Board Certification as a Medical-Surgical Nurse from Dec. 1, 1999 to Nov. 30, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Board Certification as a Medical-Surgical Nurse from Dec. 1, 2004 to Nov. 30, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Board Certification as a Medical-Surgical Nurse from Dec. 1, 2009 to Nov. 30, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series II: Awards
  - Appreciation poster and magazine cover (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Radiological Nurses Association Texas Gulf Coast Chapter plaque in appreciation of outstanding service as President 1981-1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Radiological Nurses Association plaque, President 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Philippine Nurses Association of Metropolitan Houston Excellence Award for Nursing Administration plaque, May 7, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - M. D. Anderson Cancer Center Diversity Council in recognition of your outstanding leadership and your commitment to being a Diversity Champion, plaque, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 7)